<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-31T12:11:49-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Brady Klein</title><subtitle>I'm a Computer Science student at the Jeffrey S. Raikes School of Computer Science and Management at the University of Nebraska Lincoln.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">On Simplicity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/2018/07/31/simplicity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Simplicity" /><published>2018-07-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-07-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/2018/07/31/simplicity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/2018/07/31/simplicity.html">&lt;p&gt;Nature tends towards simplicity. My high school physics teacher said that on multiple occasions, and I saw that it was true in physics; things in the world tend to follow simple polynomial relations. For instance, something as monumental as gravity is governed by multiplication and division. There aren’t any logarithms, or other complex algorithms. Pure elegance and simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until recently, I didn’t understand how universal the idea of simplicity is. I believe Bill Gates once said that he would choose a lazy worker over a perfectionist any day, because the lazy worker would find the easiest way possible to solve a problem. But even beyond Bill Gates, the world shows preference to simple solutions. Many people in the US favor a flat tax instead of a progressive tax system, because it would simplify the whole process of taxation and close loopholes. I don’t personally know that such a system would work as intended, but I can understand the desire to find a fair and simple solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regularly, I would try to find convoluted ways of doing something just to prove that I was capable of doing so. If I had to guess the cause of this, I’d say that I likely did this subconsciously, since I’m a naturally competitive person, and those complex solutions proved my intellectual superiority. Of course, the idea itself is flawed, because I was just finding a way to compete in which I could win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I since have realized that true intelligence doesn’t make itself known through complicated solutions, but rather, in finding the simplest solution possible. If I wrote 1000 lines of code just to print “Hello, World!” to the console, I wouldn’t be smart for doing so. In fact, I’d be extraordinarily stupid. All I actually need to do in order to make my computer talk to me is to open a bash terminal and type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello, World!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know, maybe that’s just a minimalist design philosophy, but I strongly think that simplicity and elegance would outclass clunky and complex any day. I actually chose this theme for my website, not only because it was the default, but because I felt like the other themes are just flash that take away from the important part of the site: its content. I could certainly write a huge, flashy, and fluid website, but I wrote this so that people could get to know me, not my code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually bought a game recently that drove the idea home for me. The game’s called &lt;em&gt;Stardew Valley&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s a pretty great game, especially considering it was entirely made by one person, and now, it’s a phenomenon. The subreddit r/StardewValley has over 211,000 subscribers, and the game was released to critical acclaim, currently garnering 97% positive reviews on Steam as of this writing, and getting ports to Xbox One, Playstation 4, and Nintendo Switch soon after it was released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The premise of the game is that your character worked for a soul-crushing company until they couldn’t stand it anymore, and moved out to the coast so they could farm on the land they inherited from their grandfather. And then, after your miniscule introduction, the world is yours to do what you wish with. Want to become a tycoon of agriculture? You can. Want to adventure deep within the unexplored mines near town? You can. Want to revitalize a dying town? You can. The possibilities are seemingly endless, but the underlying design is so simple. You have a set of tools that you can upgrade, and the world is your oyster. It’s almost similar to another popular open-ended game, &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt;, but there are certainly different aspects. &lt;em&gt;Stardew Valley&lt;/em&gt; has a complex system of relations with NPC’s, and a heavier focus on gaining money as a mechanism to interact with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without going into full game review mode, I’ll move on. Suffice it to say, I really enjoy the game. A relaxing soundtrack coupled with nostalgic pixel art left me hooked, where AAA productions like Dishonored 2 failed to really capture my attention. Sure, they’re fun, and I enjoyed them, but they just didn’t strike me the same way. In general, I think I’ve begun to notice that. My phone has a few essential apps I use all the time, like messaging apps, Reddit, Netflix, but apart from that, I don’t really have games on it, or extraneous productivity apps, mostly because I don’t need them. When I was in high school, I wore different clothes every day, to the point where I might have gone a month without repeating a shirt. Once I got into college, I decluttered. Granted, I still brought way more than I needed to my freshman year (as my roommate can attest), but I’ll continue reducing. I actually prided myself on my large collection of shoes that I got on sale, but now, during the summer and spring, I wear (mostly) one of my two pairs of Birkenstocks, during the fall and winter when there’s no snow, I wear one of my two pairs of sneakers, and when there’s snow, I wear Timberland boots. From well over 30 pairs to 5. Of course, if I need to dress up, I can wear dress shoes, but generally speaking, I don’t really wear anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve really taken this idea of simplicity to heart. Especially now, with information overload and FOMO and hyperconnectivity, it feels good to have parts of my life that don’t feel like they’re weighing me down. I think that’s a big reason why minimalist design has really gotten big in the 21st century. In the 50’s, everything felt sleek, and futuristic, which reflected the techcnological changes that the world was experiencing. I mean, there were people alive in the 50’s who grew up in the Reconstruction post-Civil War. Now, people have grown up with all the aspects of the future that make us tired of it. Many people have been trying to reconnect with their roots in various ways. In fact, there’s a large movement for Pleistocene Rewilding, which basically means trying to undo the damage that  humans have done to the landscape. For instance, wolves were hunted to extinction in Yellowstone, and that caused a series of ecological disasters. Deer became abundant, which lead to lower levels of vegetation, which in turn lead to greater levels of erosion, causing fragments and drastic bows in rivers. But, when wolves were reintroduced in Yellowstone, those changes reversed. Now that humanity has evolved to the point where we can live in the way we desire without causing harm to the world around us, we have a duty, I think, to reverse what we had to do to get us here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="random" /><category term="random" /><category term="showerthoughts" /><category term="videogames" /><summary type="html">Nature tends towards simplicity. My high school physics teacher said that on multiple occasions, and I saw that it was true in physics; things in the world tend to follow simple polynomial relations. For instance, something as monumental as gravity is governed by multiplication and division. There aren’t any logarithms, or other complex algorithms. Pure elegance and simplicity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Have Never Been Satisfied</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/2018/07/26/satisfied.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Have Never Been Satisfied" /><published>2018-07-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-07-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/2018/07/26/satisfied</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/2018/07/26/satisfied.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/HvHXTZ&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;You have married an Icarus; he has flown to close to the sun&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Greek writers seem to have some sort of obsession with dissatisfaction leading back to ruin. There’s the tale of Icarus flying too close to the sun, as well as Pandora’s box. In fact, being satisfied is considered by many people to be a virtue. Some Christian preachers once taught that we were given a certain lot in life, and that we &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; pray for forgiveness from an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiRqrLbgL3cAhUJQ60KHbjwBIMQFgg7MAE&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.jonathan-edwards.org%2FSinners.pdf&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw25oLwfCFfG06_0yaC5OCx7&quot;&gt;angry God&lt;/a&gt;. Slavers taught their slaves that they were born to serve, that they should be satisfied with what they had. Buddhism teaches that desires should be eliminated from the mind in order to attain enlightenment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed these sorts of stories and teachings for a long time, but I never really &lt;em&gt;got&lt;/em&gt; them, insofar as I couldn’t understand why people would want to be satisfied in life. As you might have guessed from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/iLnyjk&quot;&gt;title&lt;/a&gt; of this post, I not only love the musical &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;, but I really identify with the struggle that the titular character faces. Hamilton didn’t know how to be satisfied with his life. There was always something new to do, some battle to be fought. That was a good attitude to have, until he actually had the things for which he was fighting. His desire kept him alive and helped him, until finally he desired something that was out of reach, and had tragedy befall him as a result, a la Icarus. Not only that, but his desires harmed those he loved. His desire to start a national bank indirectly caused his son’s death (the national bank was unpopular, his son was arrogant, and challenged a detractor to a duel, where his son was killed) and caused his temporary estrangement from his wife through the Reynolds Pamphlet (at this point, I’m going to stop linking the Hamilton songs I reference, and just tell you to listen the musical).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the question I asked myself was the following: &lt;em&gt;How do we know when to “turn off” our desire, and furthermore,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;we turn off our desire?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but I think that’s a pretty hard question to answer. On one hand, we as a people have been taught these stories time and time again; history shows us plenty of examples of desire going too far, and “those that do not remember their past are condemned to repeat their mistakes.” But on the other, maybe the lesson isn’t that dissatisfaction is the enemy, but rather that it’s a tool. I believe that, when controlled, dissatisfaction leads to great things. Though Hamilton’s mistakes devastated his personal life, we &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; use his economic system today. The National Bank is such a good idea, most developed nations followed suit. Despite the fact that numerous Democratic-Republicans tried to undo the system, they failed. In that sense, Hamilton is a hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desire can make people richer than their wildest dreams, as it does in &lt;em&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/em&gt;, which is based on a true story, or in &lt;em&gt;The Secret of My Success&lt;/em&gt;, not based on a true story. The American Dream is someone who comes from nothing is able to make something of themselves. Tech startups across the nation have come to be multibillion dollar companies. Think about Microsoft starting from nothing, or Apple starting in a garage. The common factor between all of them is a fundamental dissatisfaction with their place in life, a desire to change the way things worked; in fact, a recent book on the subject of innovation was titled &lt;em&gt;Move Fast and Break Things&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest thing I’ve learned from thinking about the subject is that the most influential conflict of this decade won’t be the US and Russia. or the US and North Korea, or any manmade conflict. Rather, this decade has been characterized by a fundamental shift (a pivot, if you’ll pardon my business terminology) of ideas. In 2010, we still were trapped in the way that people have thought for thousands of years. In 2018, plenty of people are still in the mindset of satisfaction, and patience. We’ll call those people Burrs. But, more and more people are beginning to prize dissatisfaction and disruptive thinking. Those people we’ll call Hamiltons. Burrs and Hamiltons approach life fundamentally differently, and I believe that they sort that way because of a specific reason: their locus of control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locus of Control is a psychological term which describes how people view and interact with the world. Burrs have what’s called an external locus of control; they view the world around them as responsible for what happens to them. To a degree, I agree. There are certain aspects of your life that you have no control over, such as what color skin you’re born with and who your parents are. But Hamiltons have an internal locus of control, meaning they view themselvs as being responsible for their own actions and whatever  happens to them, they tend to take as being their fault. Again, there are parts of this philosophy that I agree with. I think that people do have agency, that they can change their future. Overall, I think both need to be taken with a grain of salt, but in the end, Hamlitons are the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether the Hamiltonian philosophy is right or wrong, I have no idea. But I can read the writing on the walls. In the game of modern life, you innovate, or you die.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="random" /><summary type="html">You have married an Icarus; he has flown to close to the sun</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m Kind of WEIRD</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/academics/2018/07/24/people-are-weird.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I'm Kind of WEIRD" /><published>2018-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/academics/2018/07/24/people-are-weird</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/academics/2018/07/24/people-are-weird.html">&lt;p&gt;So to fulfill a requirement outside my major, I decided to take Introduction to Anthropology this summer. It’s an online course, so the whole idea of self studying in and of itself is a little weird.
I also thought that to a degree, I’d have a hard time actually motivating myself to actually complete the work, but, to my surprise, the material was interesting enough that I actually completed much of
it ahead of time. I guess this really should not have come as much a surprise, considering I’d taken courses in psychology and sociology before and enjoyed them, but for some reason, anthropology seemed,
well, &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe it’s because anthropology is just on a larger scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a project in that anthroplogy class, I was required to observe a mixed gender group of 4 or more people and record which person was the dominant speaker during each minute for 30 minutes. Even though,
in reality, it wasn’t that long, I felt strange being an observer in a kind of interaction that I normally am much more involved in, as I’m a pretty talkative person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t even bother sharing the results because they were so specific that they could never be generalized to a statement of scientific value, but suffice it to say, the results were about what I expected, which brings an interesting idea to mind. In my 19 years of life, I’ve noticed that people tend to break your expectations when you least expect it, and when you most expect a departure from your preconceived notions, lo and behold, you’re proven correct.
The best way I can summarize it is that regardless of what you expect, humans will break that expectation. I think that’s a pretty uncanny ability to have, especially considering the 80 odd years of behavioral studies we’ve conducted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a scientist by the name of Joe Heinrich, the social sciences are overly skewed to weird people. Wait, I meant WEIRD people. WEIRD is an acronym used by Heinrich which means Western, Educated, Industrialized, Rich, and Democratic; Heinrich says that WEIRD people are often the subjects of experiments because, often as not, they are the subjects available at universities. The people readily available have been mostly young students at the university for which the researcher works.
Because of this fact, Heinrich has been taking anthropological, sociological, and psychological experiments on the road to determine if non-WEIRD people behave the same as WEIRD ones do. Coming as a surprise to almost no one, they don’t behave the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason I bring that up is because I think that for much of my early life, I was exposed to my sort of WEIRD people. By that, I just mean that whatever I am, people were generally pretty close to me in socioeconomic status. But as I’ve gotten older, gone to college, and especially as I’ve met more people not from the US, my eyes have been widened so to speak.
Being raised WEIRD has certainly affected my outlook on life; at the very least, I’m more aware of my WEIRDness now, and I can try my best to take that into account when having a perspective of the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="academics" /><category term="random" /><summary type="html">So to fulfill a requirement outside my major, I decided to take Introduction to Anthropology this summer. It’s an online course, so the whole idea of self studying in and of itself is a little weird. I also thought that to a degree, I’d have a hard time actually motivating myself to actually complete the work, but, to my surprise, the material was interesting enough that I actually completed much of it ahead of time. I guess this really should not have come as much a surprise, considering I’d taken courses in psychology and sociology before and enjoyed them, but for some reason, anthropology seemed, well, different. Maybe it’s because anthropology is just on a larger scale.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is your name?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/introduction/2018/07/23/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is your name?" /><published>2018-07-23T15:21:52-05:00</published><updated>2018-07-23T15:21:52-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/introduction/2018/07/23/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/introduction/2018/07/23/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;Brady Klein. &lt;em&gt;What is your quest?!&lt;/em&gt; To make a difference through applying computer science, business, and hard science perspectives to modern problems. 
&lt;em&gt;What is your favorite color?!&lt;/em&gt; Despite being a UNL student, I have to go with green. I’m a Michigan State Spartan through and through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure exactly what this blog will become. All I know now is that it’ll at least attempt to document the important moments of my life. I might even forget about this site for a while. I haven’t decided yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, for the uninitiated, reference &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IMxWLuOFyZM&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; clip from Monty Python and the Holy Grail.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="random" /><category term="introduction" /><summary type="html">Brady Klein. What is your quest?! To make a difference through applying computer science, business, and hard science perspectives to modern problems. What is your favorite color?! Despite being a UNL student, I have to go with green. I’m a Michigan State Spartan through and through.</summary></entry></feed>